Mark Lam

1770 Dean Street Brooklyn, New York USA markofthelam.com github.com/emceelamb

+1 661 478 9651

mark@markofthelam.com

Mark Lam is a sculptor and media scholar turned developer. He has a background in visual design and has developed websites and digital design for e-commerce and independent business. Most recently he has been working towards a Master's degree at New York University where he researches media making with computer networking technology. His other interests include teaching programming, digital accessibility, and reading about media theory.

Areas of Interest

- Computer Networking for Expressive Media
- Interactive Physical-Digital Interfaces Development
- Real-time Tangible Data Visualization
- Empathetic Conceptual Development

Previous Experience

SELF-EMPLOYED

Freelance Developer HCMC, NYC, LA

2018–2019 LINCOLN CENTER FOR THE PERFORMING ARTS

Digital Accessibility Fellow

New York City

New York University - ITP

Graduate Assistant - Web Accessibility Developer

New York City

2017–2018 Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology & Education

Visiting Lecturer - Introductory Programming, English

Ho Chi Minh City

2015–2017 JKH GROUP

Website Coordinator

Valencia

Education

2020 Interactive Telecommunications

New York University, New York City

2015 Media Studies & Art Practice

University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley

2013 Graphic Design

2020

2019

2019

College of the Canyons, Valencia

Projects & Workshops

Automating Mindfulness, Technical Workshop *Unconference at ITP NYU*, New York City

- Introduction to Bash scripting
- Explore how automation can reduce mental fatigue

Network Operator, Performance

NIME 2019, New York City

- Explore computer networking technology as medium for musical expression
- · Live network programming

Lincoln Center Campus Accessibility Map, Digital Map

Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, New York City

- Create an accessible digital map of the Lincoln Center Campus
- Extend Google Maps API to incorporate WAI-ARIA features